<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

	<!-- generator="WordPress/5.2.4" created="2019-10-27 00:20" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>BLOG</title>
	<link>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud</link>
	<description>I&#039;m looking forward to expand my portfolio while i&#039;m on top and while i&#039;m young. Luis M. Alvarez brings your content to life in stunnig clarity</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud</wp:base_blog_url>

		<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[99yzjs]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[sidharth.malik@mavs.uta.edu]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[admin]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

		<wp:category>
		<wp:term_id>1</wp:term_id>
		<wp:category_nicename><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></wp:category_nicename>
		<wp:category_parent><![CDATA[]]></wp:category_parent>
		<wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></wp:cat_name>
	</wp:category>
				<wp:term>
		<wp:term_id><![CDATA[1]]></wp:term_id>
		<wp:term_taxonomy><![CDATA[category]]></wp:term_taxonomy>
		<wp:term_slug><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></wp:term_slug>
		<wp:term_parent><![CDATA[]]></wp:term_parent>
		<wp:term_name><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></wp:term_name>
	</wp:term>
		
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.4</generator>

		<item>
		<title>My Hobbies</title>
		<link>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/uncategorized/hello-world/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 04:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[99yzjs]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/?p=1</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I’ve been going to the gym for about twenty years. I’m not a professional bodybuilder or fitness instructor – lifting weights is just a hobby of mine. But I’ve learned a lot over the years, and I’ve even trained some of my friends. I often give (free) advice about exercise, diet and supplements.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I asked myself this question about ten months ago: Why haven’t I created a fitness blog? I loved the topic, and I already knew the basics of blogging.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So I did it – I created&nbsp;<a href="http://www.strongandfit.net/">StrongandFit.net</a>. I started blogging, using tips I learned here at problogger.net. Slowly but surely, the traffic started coming. My fitness blog is now most visited (and most profitable) blog. My only regret is I didn’t start it sooner.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Here’s my point: I think there are millions of people who have untapped earning potential in their hobbies (a certain blogger’s digital photography hobby comes to mind). They’ve just never taken the time to share their valuable experiences and expertise online.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Here are some advantages to blogging about your hobby:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Ready-made niche</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>All the pros agree – you should choose a niche you are passionate about. Well, a hobby is something you already love enough to do with your free time. Seems like the perfect place to start!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Ready-made posts</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>You’ve probably already invested time, effort, and money into your hobby. Maybe you’ve even answered questions about it or shown others how to get involved. In other words, you probably already have dozens of posts swimming around in your head. All you have to do is take the time and write them down.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Ready-made affiliate opportunities</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Most hobbies have books, magazines, equipment, or other products/services. You’ve probably already invested in some of these and formed an opinion regarding which are most valuable. In other words, you are already set to endorse certain products. Your reviews could earn money and help others make good choices.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Re-Energize your hobby</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Blogging could get you more involved in something you’re already passionate about. It could even get you back into something you once enjoyed. The process of blogging (research, forums, etc) has an energy to it that ads to the fun.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>No expertise necessary</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>What if you are a novice? No problem! Just be honest about it and invite others along your journey – share what you are doing. Here’s an example from the fitness niche: I’ve seen several blogs created by overweight individuals who want to document their weight loss journey. Some of these are quite inspirational.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>If you never make money, it’s OK – its just a hobby</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As Darren has pointed out, most of us probably won’t make big money from blogging. My blog is making a little money for me, but I’m nowhere near ready to quit my day job. But that’s the beauty of a hobby blog – you’ll have so much fun you’ll be willing to wait for the profits.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Final Thoughts:</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>You have a hobby, don’t you? What are you waiting for? Start a blog and monetize it! You have nothing to lose.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-24 04:01:45]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-24 04:01:45]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[hello-world]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
						<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[A WordPress Commenter]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[wapuu@wordpress.example]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>https://wordpress.org/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2019-10-24 04:01:37]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-24 04:01:37]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi, this is a comment.
To get started with moderating, editing, and deleting comments, please visit the Comments screen in the dashboard.
Commenter avatars come from <a href="https://gravatar.com">Gravatar</a>.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
							</wp:comment>
					</item>
					<item>
		<title>Sample Page</title>
		<link>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/sample-page/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 04:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[99yzjs]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/?page_id=2</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is an example page. It's different from a blog post because it will stay in one place and will show up in your site navigation (in most themes). Most people start with an About page that introduces them to potential site visitors. It might say something like this:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Hi there! I'm a bike messenger by day, aspiring actor by night, and this is my website. I live in Los Angeles, have a great dog named Jack, and I like pi&#241;a coladas. (And gettin' caught in the rain.)</p></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>...or something like this:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:quote -->
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>The XYZ Doohickey Company was founded in 1971, and has been providing quality doohickeys to the public ever since. Located in Gotham City, XYZ employs over 2,000 people and does all kinds of awesome things for the Gotham community.</p></blockquote>
<!-- /wp:quote -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As a new WordPress user, you should go to <a href="http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/wp-admin/">your dashboard</a> to delete this page and create new pages for your content. Have fun!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-24 04:01:45]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-24 04:01:45]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[sample-page]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
														<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Privacy Policy</title>
		<link>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/?page_id=3</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 04:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[99yzjs]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/?page_id=3</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:heading --><h2>Who we are</h2><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>Our website address is: http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading --><h2>What personal data we collect and why we collect it</h2><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>Comments</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor&#8217;s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>Media</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>Contact forms</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>Cookies</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>If you visit our login page, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select &quot;Remember Me&quot;, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>Embedded content from other websites</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>Analytics</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading --><h2>Who we share your data with</h2><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading --><h2>How long we retain your data</h2><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading --><h2>What rights you have over your data</h2><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading --><h2>Where we send your data</h2><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --><p>Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.</p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading --><h2>Your contact information</h2><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading --><h2>Additional information</h2><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>How we protect your data</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>What data breach procedures we have in place</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>What third parties we receive data from</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data</h3><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --><h3>Industry regulatory disclosure requirements</h3><!-- /wp:heading -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>3</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-24 04:01:45]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-24 04:01:45]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[privacy-policy]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[draft]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
														<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title>Skills in UI</title>
		<link>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/uncategorized/skills/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 22:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[99yzjs]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/?p=10</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>First things first - what is UI design?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>User Interface Design is a crucial subset of UX. They both share the same end goal - to provide a positive experience for the user - but UI Design comprises an entirely separate leg of the journey.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:image -->
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img alt=""/></figure>
<!-- /wp:image -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4 id="ui-design-the-visual">UI Design: The Visual</h4>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>UI design focuses on the user’s visual experience. It determines how a user interacts with an interface - be it an app, a video game or a website. It’s all about how the user navigates from A to B via different visual touch points. Think tapping a button or swiping through pictures.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The job of a UI designer is to design all the screens through which a user will move, and to create the visual elements - and their interactive properties - that facilitate this movement.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4 id="ui-design-the-human">UI Design: The Human</h4>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At the same time, a UI designer works with human behavior in mind.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>How so?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Look at it this way. A good interface requires barely any thought from the user. Consider your favorite app: it’s easy on the eye and simple to use, right? When you first installed it, you didn’t spend ages working out how to get from A to B - it was just obvious.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The UI designer is pivotal to this. They think about the human user and how the mind works. They use things like patterns, spacing and color to guide the user.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“Intuitive” is the keyword here. Not only is the UI designer a creative creature; they also put themselves in the user’s shoes, anticipating what they expect at each stage. They then use this empathy to design visual, interactive elements that respond in a way that feels natural to the user.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Let’s say you’re using an app to look for a new apartment. One listing in particular catches your eye, so you click to view the gallery. A full-size image takes over your screen, captioned 1/5. You know there are more pictures, so you use your finger to swipe through the gallery. There were no instructions to do so - somehow, you just knew.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is the work of the UI designer. They think about what the user will expect, and design the app’s interface accordingly.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In a nutshell: UX draws out the map, the bare bones. UI then fleshes them out with visual, interactive touch points that take the user through their journey as intuitively as possible.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3 id="what-tasks-can-a-ui-designer-expect">What Tasks Can a UI Designer Expect?</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So, it’s the UI designer’s job to bring the UX designer’s vision to life. But how do they go about this?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Of course, your role will vary greatly depending on whether you’re in-house or freelance, and the kinds of projects you work on.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>However, pretty much every UI designer can expect the following:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":4} -->
<h4 id="collaboration">Collaboration</h4>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As a UI designer, you should be prepared to collaborate with others. From the client and the UX designer, right through to the developers - communication is key at every stage.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At the start of the process especially, you can expect to work closely with both the client and the UX designer. UI is all about humans, after all, so you’ll need to spend some time getting to know the brand and its target user. What goals drive the user as they move around your interface, and what are their expectations?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>User research and personas tend to fall under UX - but it’s the UI designer’s job to take this information and run with it. The UX designer will most likely provide you with a wireframe from which to work.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Finally, you’ll need to hand your design over to the developers. Ultimately, building a rapport across different teams and being able to communicate clearly are crucial to the success of your project.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-25 22:35:58]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-25 22:35:58]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[skills]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
						</item>
					<item>
		<title>Research in AI</title>
		<link>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/uncategorized/research-in-ai/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 22:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[99yzjs]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/?p=12</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The strategy I have come to adopt for writing research code is to start by creating visualization scripts. When the rest of the code has been written, running the visualization scripts will allow me to quickly verify whether my code matches my mental model. Even more importantly, good visualizations will often make bugs in my thinking or code far more obvious and interpretable than they would be otherwise. There is also something to be said here for self-motivation: when I finish this code, I will have a pretty figure or video to show people!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Coming up with the right visualization for the problem at hand can be tricky. If you are iteratively optimizing a model (e.g. deep learning), plotting loss curves is always a good place to start. There are also many techniques for visualizing and interpreting learned weights of (especially convolutional) neural networks such as guided backpropagation (e.g. <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1412.6806.pdf">guided backpropagation</a>). In reinforcement learning and planning, the obvious thing to visualize is the agent acting in its environment, be it an Atari game, a robotic task, or a simple grid world (e.g. the environments in <a href="https://gym.openai.com/envs">OpenAI Gym</a>). Depending on the setup, it may also be possible to visualize the value function and how it changes over the course of training (shown below), or the tree of explored states. When dealing with graphical models, visualizing the distribution of a one or two dimensional variable as it changes over inference can be highly informative (shown below). One barometer for the effectiveness of a visualization technique is to estimate the amount of information that you have to hold in your head everytime you analyze a visualization. A bad visualization will require recalling in detail the code you wrote to produce it; a good one will scream an obvious conclusion.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I have heard two common pieces of advice regarding the amount of time one should spend with prior work. First, when just starting out, read all of the papers! People often say that the first semester or year of graduate school should be nothing but paper reading. Second, presumably beyond this initial ramp-up period, do not spend too much time reading papers! The rationale for the latter being that it is easier to creatively pose and solve problems if one is not biased towards previous approaches.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Personally, I agree with the first bit of advice and disagree with the second. I think one should read as many papers as possible always, so long as there is still time left over for original research. The notion that I will be better equipped to come up with a novel, superior approach to a hard problem if I am unfamiliar with what others have tried seems unlikely at best and arrogant at worst. Yes, a fresh perspective on a problem can be key, and yes, stories of amateurs solving longstanding challenges because of their outside-the-box thinking are inspiring (e.g.&nbsp;<a href="https://curiosity.com/topics/how-george-dantzigs-late-arrival-to-class-made-math-history-curiosity/">George Dantzig</a>&nbsp;showing up late to lecture). But a career researcher cannot really depend on these fortunate jumps to sections of solution space not yet considered. The vast majority of time is spent patiently following the gradient, chipping away at a problem slowly and methodically. Reading relevant papers then is just a far more efficient way to figure out where we are and what to try next. (See also Julian Togelius on "<a href="http://togelius.blogspot.com/2016/04/the-differences-between-tinkering-and.html">tinkering versus research</a>.")</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>12</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-25 22:45:28]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-25 22:45:28]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[research-in-ai]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
						</item>
					<item>
		<title>Game Developement</title>
		<link>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/uncategorized/game-developement/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 22:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[99yzjs]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/?p=17</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Game Development is the art of creating games and describes the design, development and release of a game. It may involve concept generation, design, build, test and release. While you create a game, it is important to think about the game mechanics, rewards, player engagement and level design.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A game developer could be a programmer, a sound designer, an artist, a designer or many other roles available in the industry.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Game Development can be undertaken by a large Game Development Studio or by a single individual. It can be as small or large as you like. As long as it lets the player interact with content and is able to manipulate the game’s elements, you can call it a ‘game’.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>To get involved in the Game Development process, you do not need to write code. Artists may create and design assets, while a Developer might focus on programming a health bar. A Tester may get involved to see that the game works as expected.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p> To resolve problems that game frameworks had, tools like libGDX and OpenGL were developed. They helped game development to be a lot faster and easier, providing lots of pre-made functions and features. However, it was still hard to enter the industry or understand a framework for someone coming from a non-programmer background, a common case in the game development scene. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Many developers choose to develop a game using a Game Development Engine.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Game Engines can make the process of creating a game much easier and enable developers to reuse lots of functionality. It also takes care of rendering for 2D and 3D Graphics, physics and collision detection, sound, scripting and much more.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Some Game Engines have a very steep learning curve such as CryEngine or Unreal Engine. Yet, other tools are very accessible to beginners and some do not even need you to be able to write code to create your game, e.g. Construct 2.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The Unity Game Engine ranges somewhere in the middle, while it is beginner friendly, some popular and commercial games have been built using Unity (e.g. Overcooked, Superhot).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The BuildBox game engine is basically for developing hypercasual games.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Typical Game Engines</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>CryEngine</li><li>Unreal Engine</li><li>Unity Game Engine</li><li>Game Maker</li><li>Construct 2 or 3</li><li>Twine</li><li>Source</li><li>Frostbite</li><li>Buildbox</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>17</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-25 22:56:12]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-25 22:56:12]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[game-developement]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
						</item>
					<item>
		<title>Web Developement</title>
		<link>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/uncategorized/web-developement/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 23:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[99yzjs]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/?p=19</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For those who build websites with WordPress, this moment seems like one of great possibilities mixed in with a lot of uncertainty. Gutenberg brings with it the ability to create more complex layouts than the Classic Editor. Yet, for some this might not be quite enough.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>While the block editor can be expanded via building custom blocks or third-party plugins, it still lacks the fit and finish of an established page builder. And even though custom blocks are an exciting concept, they present a major barrier to entry for those of us who are not JavaScript experts.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>True, we can get around this obstacle with&nbsp;<a href="https://speckyboy.com/custom-blocks-gutenberg-block-lab/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">plugins</a>&nbsp;that do some of the heavy lifting for us. But to take full advantage of Gutenberg, it’s going to require the commitment of time and money to become educated. For a busy freelancer, this can be a challenge.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As for our clients, that’s another issue. A new editor means retraining clients to learn the nuances of Gutenberg – even as it continues to evolve. This is certainly an opportunity to&nbsp;<a href="https://speckyboy.com/wordpress-gutenberg-boost-revenue/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">increase revenue</a>. But again, a solo entrepreneur or even a small team only has so much time for client education. Thus, there’s a real temptation to&nbsp;<a href="https://speckyboy.com/wordpress-classic-editor-new-websites/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stick with</a>&nbsp;the Classic Editor for a bit longer.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When it comes to building websites, it feels like we are at a crossroads. Figuring out the right path for both ourselves and our clients is both crucial and incredibly difficult. The decisions we make now are ones we will have to live with for years to come.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>19</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-25 23:04:08]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-25 23:04:08]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[web-developement]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
						</item>
					<item>
		<title>logo2</title>
		<link>http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/logo2/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 21:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[99yzjs]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/logo2.png</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>25</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2019-10-26 21:09:22]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2019-10-26 21:09:22]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[logo2]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
						<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://sidharthmalik.uta.cloud/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/logo2.png]]></wp:attachment_url>
											<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2019/10/logo2.png]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:200;s:6:"height";i:27;s:4:"file";s:17:"2019/10/logo2.png";s:5:"sizes";a:1:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:16:"logo2-150x27.png";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:27;s:9:"mime-type";s:9:"image/png";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_custom_header_last_used_twentysixteen]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1572124195]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_is_custom_header]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[twentysixteen]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>
	